completetax.com 2011-11-01

# Privacy Policy

Our Commitment to Privacy  
  
This Service is provided to you through CCH INCORPORATED ("CCH"), the owner of this product. CCH is committed to keeping your information private and recognizes the importance all customers place on the privacy and confidentiality of their information. While new technologies allow us to more efficiently serve our clients, we are committed to maintaining the rigorous privacy standards that are synonymous with our established and trusted name.

By participating in the Council of Better Business Bureau's BBBOnLine® Privacy Program we have made a commitment to meet the program's strict requirements regarding how we treat your information and have it verified by BBBOnLine®. Further information about this program is available at [http://www.bbbonline.org](http://www.bbbonline.org/).

CCH, Inc. has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [support@completetax.com](mailto:support@completetax.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [ TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

In keeping with our Privacy Policy, we provide this Policy explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this Policy easy to find, we make it available throughout our web site and on other pages throughout our web site.  
  
Covered Web Sites

The Privacy Policy described herein is applicable to this entire web site, including all areas where financial information is gathered and income tax data is input, printed and/or transmitted. It does not apply to any other online services, or to any other web sites published and/or maintained by us or any other service provider.

This Privacy Policy covers all the online information practices of www.completetax.com. Other sites maintained by CCH, such as www.tax.cchgroup.com and www.tax.cchgroup.com/pfx/products/CompleteTaxPro/ operate under their own Privacy and security policies.

**Please Note:** Our Service is applicable to filers of resident U.S. Federal income tax returns only, and accordingly the statements made in this Privacy Policy apply solely to residents of the United States.  
  
Our Commitment to Data Security 

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures designed to safeguard and secure the personal information and email address we collect online.

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number, or national ID) on our forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).  
  
Internal Controls

When collecting, storing and retrieving your personal data, extensive internal controls are maintained throughout the process that are designed to ensure security and confidentiality.

Our Internet-based systems are protected behind firewalls, and all mission critical servers are deployed in a cluster environment to provide an even greater level of security and protection against system failure. All data is maintained and backed-up on a regular schedule to provide adequate redundancy and as part of an effort to ensure that the integrity of information is never jeopardized.

Our employees are subject to strict guidelines regarding confidentiality, and internal access to customer data is restricted to highly trained personnel on an "as-needed" basis and in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.  
  
Transmitting Information

When transmitting information between you and our server, as well as when communicating with the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) for electronic filing, data security is handled through a protocol called Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). SSL is an established and mature Internet security standard with two dominant features: data encryption and web server authentication.  
  
The Information We Collect

This Policy applies to all information collected or submitted on our web site. You may start your tax return for free, the information collected at this time in order to create an account is: 

Name  
User ID  
Password  
E-mail Address  
Security Question  

When submitting a tax return we ask for sensitive information (such as your social security number, Tax ID, or national ID).

If a credit card is used to pay for the Service or the live chat feature that we offer, in addition to tax return information, we collect the following credit card and personal information: 

Cardholder's Name  
Credit Card Type  
Credit Card Number  
Expiration Date  
Cardholder's Billing Address  
Daytime Phone Number  
E-mail Address  
Employer's or Relative's Phone Number  

The credit card information is used to process your transaction. This information is not made available to anyone else other than our third party credit card processor.

We also collect the following information for use in answering your inquiries for technical support when you submit an email requesting our assistance: 

Your Name  
User ID  
E-mail Address  
Operating System  
Browser Type  
Connection Type/Speed  

Tell-A-Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. CCH, Inc does not store this information.   
  
Customer Testimonials

We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain a photo of you. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their photo along with their testimonial. To request removal of your personal information from our testimonials, click [ this link](http://tax.cchgroup.com/cforms/newsletters/taa-unsubscribe.aspx?leadsource=unsubscribe-completetax). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.   
  
Use of Cookies

We use "cookies" on our websites to personalize and enhance your website visits. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard drive by our web server. Cookies are uniquely assigned to a computer, and your computer will only allow our web servers to access our cookies. The most important thing to understand about cookies is that they pose no danger to you. They cannot be used to collect personal information about you or your computer or to provide information about you to other companies.

Cookies provide a convenience by saving you time on subsequent visits and personalizing your web experience. For example, when you return to our website, cookies enable us to remember information from prior visits such as your user ID. Cookies may save data such as name, password, user ID, screen preferences, pages viewed, and ads clicked. Credit card information and personal information is never saved in cookies.

You have the right to delete cookies placed on your hard drive, which will erase the data automatically saved during your visit. However that will mean that our sites will not recognize you when you return. You may also modify your web browser to notify you before accepting cookies, or to decline all cookies. We strongly suggest that you accept cookies from us, since they help provide you a more seamless, personalized, and effective web browsing experience and keep our site compelling and informative.  
  
Third Party Cookies

The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. These third parties use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site, in order for you to use the shopping cart.   
  
Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

Our third party advertising partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information. 

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see "Choice and Opt-out."   
  
The Way We Use Information 

We do not share, sell, rent, or trade your personal information or email address with third parties, other than as disclosed within this privacy policy. 

The tax return information that we collect is used strictly for lawful purposes and is never shared with Federal, State or other taxing authorities without your consent. The foregoing notwithstanding, we reserve the right to disclose your information without your consent as required by law, and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, in response to a court order, legal process served on our Web site, subpoena, search warrant or other inquiry or request from governmental or regulatory authorities, or to protect against fraud or other criminal activities. If you choose to electronically file your return, we will transmit your tax return to the appropriate Federal and State taxing authorities. 

The IRS requires us to provide the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer from which the return originated, as well as the e-mail address of the person who electronically filed the return. This information is sent to the IRS at the time you choose to submit your return to the IRS for electronic filing.

In order to electronically file your return, we must share your submitted tax information with the appropriate tax authorities in order to complete your request. You can control whether or not you wish your tax information shared for this purpose by deciding whether or not to complete the tax return forms, which are all clearly labeled.

The above listed credit card information that we collect will be used strictly for order processing and billing purposes, and will not be shared with any other party other than the credit card processing company and the IRS in order to implement your direct deposit request. When appropriate, bank account or credit card information is also passed to our bank, for processing purposes, if you choose to use our Credit Card Payment of Balance Due or Deduct Fee from Refund options. You will enter this information during the routine course of a purchase. In the event that our Internet Service staff should need to research and resolve any status or billing issues associated with an order, the information will only be accessed by authorized personnel. 

Our Basic Service entitles you to notification via e-mail of filing deadlines, estimate reminders, tax law changes, as well as tax planning and financial information that may affect your tax return. In order for us to provide you with the Basic Service, it is required that you provide us with your e-mail address.

Personally identifiable information is only shared as indicated in this document or as otherwise consented to by you in writing, subject to compliance with all applicable laws and regulations.

If you sign up for our newsletter, we will use your email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions in each newsletter or by clicking [this link](http://tax.cchgroup.com/cforms/newsletters/taa-unsubscribe.aspx?leadsource=unsubscribe-completetax).   
  
Consent to Use Information

Your use of the Service means that you consent to CCH's and Affiliate's access and review of your tax return information necessary to provide you with the Basic Service described above.

In addition, we may provide you with promotional messages. If you wish to opt-out of receiving such promotional messages, you may click [this link](http://tax.cchgroup.com/cforms/newsletters/taa-unsubscribe.aspx?leadsource=unsubscribe-completetax) or write to CCH INCORPORATED, Online Tax Group - MS 28, 21250 Hawthorne Boulevard, Torrance, CA 90503. Declining to receive e-mail promotional messages will not affect CCH's and Affiliate's ability to deliver the Basic Service to you.  
  
Third Party Services 

For the purpose of providing you with additional information or services, our web site may also provide links or references to our other web sites or to third party web sites of online information providers, advertisers, and other business partners. When offering partner services the partner who will be receiving your information will be clearly identified.

We are not responsible for information gathered by third party web sites. You should review any third party site's Privacy Policy for details regarding their policies concerning information they gather. Any time you are preparing to navigate to a site that is not covered by this Privacy Policy, we will indicate at the bottom of the page that you are leaving our site.

We use Live Chat to assist you if you have questions while using our site or regarding your tax return. When you sign up for our services we will collect personal information from you such as your name and email address and billing information such as credit card number and expiration date. We use this information to bill you for the live chat service and may provide this information as necessary for the third party to provide that service. 

Through our partnership with Santa Barbara Bank & Trust ("SBBT"), you may apply for a bank product. In order to apply for a bank product, you must consent to our disclosure of your relevant personal and tax return information to SBBT. Signing the necessary consent form for such disclosure included within the program serves as your authorization. Your tax information is sent to SBBT when your return is e-filed. When you select the option within our program for a bank product, once your return has qualified for electronic filing we share some or all of the following for SBBT to provide the requested service: your name, address, social security number, phone number, amount of refund and bank account information. SBBT uses the personally identifiable information for the purpose of providing your bank product. You may visit the site at <https://cisc.sbbtral.com/privacy.aspx> to view their Privacy Policy.

Through our partnership with Official Payments Corporation®, you may request to pay your tax balance due via credit or debit card. When you make this request, you will be asked to disclose your card information to Official Payments. Official Payments uses the personally identifiable information for the purpose of providing the payment of your tax via credit or debit card as requested. You may visit the site at [www.officialpayments.com](http://www.officialpayments.com/cch.jsp) to view their Privacy Policy.

Information entered into the donation value calculators (through CharityDeductions.com™) is used solely to provide you with information regarding the fair market value of non-cash charitable donations. You may visit the site at [www.charitydeductions.com](http://www.charitydeductions.com/) to view their Privacy Policy.

Information entered into the Tax Calculators (through Time Value Software) is used solely to provide you with estimates of various tax situations. The information used in these calculations is not saved. You may visit the site at [www.tvalue.com](http://www.timevalue.com/privacy.aspx) to view their Privacy Policy.  
  
Co-Branded Sites

Some pages may have the look and feel of being on a third party site, however the information collected on these pages is covered by our privacy policy. All information collected on www.internet-taxprep is owned and controlled by our privacy policy.

At times we may enter into co-branded relationships. When we enter into these types of relationships we will share your name and email address in order for our co-branded partner to send you promotional messages and information about other products and services that may be of interest to you.

Our privacy statement does apply to the information collected on these co-branded sites.  
  
Retrieving Your Information

Our Service is available for starting, completing and e-filing your return from approximately mid-January through mid-October of each tax year. To view your return information, you may use your User ID and Password to access a free summary report and/or pay a fee to print, view, and electronically file your actual return. Once you have paid, you may continue to access, modify and/or print your tax return as often as needed during this time.

From mid-October through mid-December you can still complete and mail your return to the appropriate filing authorities if you began it prior to mid-October. Simply click on the "Continue Your Return" selection on the "Prepare Your Return" menu.

If your personally identifiable information or email address changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct or update it by making the change within your account by clicking on "Manage/Edit your account information" or by emailing our Customer Support at [support@completetax.com](mailto:support@completetax.com).

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at support@completetax.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

After paying for your return, the financial information used to make your payment (e.g. credit card number), as well as the record of your payment, will not be retrievable by you.  
  
Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy or email practices, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.  
  
How to Contact Us

Should you have other questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please submit your questions using our Customer Support link or one of the methods below.

CCH INCORPORATED  
Online Tax Group - Suite 200  
20101 Hamilton Avenue  
Torrance, CA 90502  
Email: [support@completetax.com](mailto:support@completetax.com)  
Web site URL: [www.completetax.com](http://www.completetax.com/)  

Effective September 27, 2010

© 2010-2011, CCH. All Rights Reserved.  
CCH, a Wolters Kluwer business
